# Hello, I'm James.

My most recent working history is at Apple, where I spent 11 years working my way from a part-time role in sales, to manager.

I had planned to celebrate my 10 years with a sabbatical adventuring through Thailand, Japan and Europe - but it ended up being a year spent just in the far north of Thailand, thanks to the ol' pandemic.

I made the absolute most of it, soul-searching and falling deeper in love with the warm Thai air and the mountains - and have come home owning half an acre of land I can't wait to go back and build a house on.

My existing career couldn't continue in a town with a population of 3,000 - so I thought long and hard about what I wanted to do next. I am a hopeless nerd, an absolute digital native and have an absolute passion for all things usability, accessibility and interface.

This led me to me studying UX/UI Design, and I haven't looked back. It has been so rewarding to draw on my years of experience at Apple to approach a whole new world of challenges and problems with that same creativity, minimalism focus.

Thank you!

## **Experience**

### **Apple**

### Manager

September 2015 - May 2021

Shopping (Customer & Team Experience, Performance & Results)

Created a framework of coaching, development and stretch assignments to successfully grow a critically underhired Expert team from four employees to twelve.

Genius Bar (Customer & Team Experience, Performance & Results)

While considering the needs of the business, I delivered timely, consistent, and fair schedules. Scheduling to guidance and balancing customer-facing activities helped our team focus on experience - achieving a global Ovation award for most improved as rated by our customers.

People (Talent Selection, Performance Culture, Learning & Development, Engagement)

Achieved the best hiring position for the store to date in 2018 (6.5 years in operation) and maintained a hired position for the majority of 2019.

### Leadership Experience

November 2014 - September 2015

This was a time of high growth and discovery, as I led our teams at the Genius Bar, then the entire store team while also beginning to deliver scheduling responsibilities.

#### **Lead Genius**

March 2013 - November 2014 Lead for national Pilot programs Key developer for our current Lead and Senior level employees

#### Genius

April 2011 - March 2013 New Store Opening Mentor at Apple Rundle Place Onboarding Guest Facilitator

#### **Technical Specialist**

June 2010 - March 2011

#### **Specialist**

March 2010 - May 2010

### Freelance Photographer

2009 - 2010

Worked as a generalist photographer, primarily shooting events, wedding, corporate headsets and assisting on big-ticket fashion and commercial shoots.

# Skills

User Research Problem Definition Solution Ideation Prototyping User Testing Implementation

# Education

2021 - UX/UI (Intensive) - Adelaide University

2016 - Chinese First Year (Intensive), Adelaide University

2008 - Diploma in Commercial Photography, Adelaide

2003 - Bachelor of Arts, Philosophy, Adelaide University (partial)

2001 - High School Certificate (SACE), Hamilton College

# **Passions**

Language (basic Mandarin and Thai)

Culture

Design

Usability

Muay Thai

Veganism

Kpop

Japan-Made Goods